Guide to the Eldon Barrett Papers 1849-2010
Western Washington University, Heritage Resources
Eldon Barrett Papers
1849-2010
1935-2010
Western Washington University, Heritage Resources Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7747 Email: heritage.resources@wwu.edu http://library.wwu.edu/heritageresources
XOE_CPNWS305barrett
Barrett, Eldon
14.5 linear feet
The Eldon Barrett Papers comprise biographical and personal papers, research, writings, and photographic materials documenting the life and career of a nationally known journalist, United Press International (UPI) writer and news bureau chief.
Eldon Barrett (1921-2009) was a nationally known journalist, United Press International (UPI) reporter and news bureau chief. Born in Nampa, Idaho, Barrett’s journalism career began during his teenage years at Olympia High School in Washington State, where he was a writer and editor of the school newspaper. He continued his writing at St. Martin’s College in Lacey, Washington, before enlisting in the Merchant Marine during World War II. After the war, Barrett began working for UPI news agency, initially in Salem, Oregon, and then in Seattle, Washington. In 1980, following retirement from UPI, Barrett and his wife Catherine (Ayer) Barrett moved to Bellingham, Washington, where he edited "Going Strong," a Bellingham Herald column on the topic of senior citizens, and continued to research and publish travel-related writing.
Eldon Barrett covered myriad issues and events during his career in journalism, including presidential visits to Seattle, sporting events, nuclear bomb testing in Alaska and Washington State legislative sessions. He was an avid and skilled photographer, documenting much of his travel and research interests through images as well as writing.
Sources: Eldon Barrett Papers and obituary, published 2009.
The Eldon Barrett Papers comprise biographical and personal papers, research, writings and photographic materials documenting the life and career of a nationally known journalist, United Press International (UPI) writer and news bureau chief.
The collection contains a small number of biographical and personal records, including documents from Eldon Barrett’s high school and college years, certificates of award, papers relating to his military service and a copy of his obituary.
The bulk of the collection comprises the extensive research and writing files generated through the course of Barrett’s career with UPI, and during his “retirement” years as a freelance travel writer and Bellingham Herald columnist. Maintained largely in the original and meticulous order found in Barrett's office, these files chronicle the extent and evolving nature of his research interests. His files include an assortment of notes, correspondence, articles, clippings, publications, photographs and other materials organized topically as the basis for his professional writings. These research and writings files document a wide variety of subjects, including people, places and events in the Pacific Northwest and other world-wide locations. Barrett researched and documented myriad stories of local and regional interest, including high-profile criminal cases, Pacific Northwest maritime history, WWII history in the Aleutian Islands and nuclear weapons testing at Amchitka, Alaska. Also of interest and grouped together are research files for Barrett’s Bellingham Herald “Seniors” columns, and pertaining to his ideas for books, articles, poetry and other writing projects. While Barrett frequently included copies or drafts of his manuscripts among these (subject-related) research files, researchers will also find many related and additional writings organized together under the headings “publications” and “published articles.”
Eldon Barrett's papers contain a significant number of slides, photographs and scrapbooks that complement or document his writings and other research materials. Folders, albums and scrapbooks are clearly identified on the inventory with descriptive titles (most supplied or labeled by Barrett) regarding the name, location and date of their subjects. They include slides of travels and landscapes in Western Washington and the Pacific Northwest in particular, images of Seattle and Olympia during the 1960s (including images of visiting presidents, Robert F. Kennedy and Black Panther protests in Olympia), and scrapbooks of photos and clippings documenting Barrett's work "On the Job" at UPI's Seattle office.
The collection also includes a small number of programs from sporting and other events, including the dedication ceremony for the Seattle Kingdome.
The Eldon Barrett papers are organized in accordance with the following series arrangement:
Series I. Biographical and personal papers1935-2010
Series II. Research and Writings1849-20101937-2010
Series III. Slides, Photographs and Albums circa 1930-19991960-1999
Series IV. Event Programs1961-1980
The collection is open to the public.
The Eldon Barrett Papers were donated to the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies on July 30, 2010 by his family.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Eldon Barrett, 1921-2009--Archives.
United Press International--History--Sources.; Kingdome (Seattle, Wash.)--History--Sources.
Aleutian Islands (Alaska)--History, Military--Sources.; Amchitka Island (Alaska)--History--Sources.; Northwest, Pacific--Description and travel--History--Sources.; Northwest, Pacific--Description and travel--History--Sources--Photographs.; Northwest, Pacific--History--Sources.; Northwest, Pacific--History--Sources--Photographs.; Olympia (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Olympia (Wash.)--History--Sources--Photographs.; Seattle (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Seattle (Wash.)--History--Sources--Photographs.; Washington (State)--History--Sources.; Washington (State)--History--Sources--Photographs.
Journalists--Northwest, Pacific--History--Sources.; Older people--Washington (State)--Bellingham--History--Sources.; Nuclear testing--Alaska--Amchitka Island--History--Sources.; Reporters and reporting--Northwest, Pacific--History--Sources.; World War, 1939-1945--Alaska--Aleutian Islands--History--Sources.
Journalism.; Alaska.; Bellingham.; Olympia.; Seattle.; Washington (State).
- Biographical and personal papers, 1935-2010; Series I.
  Scrapbook of additional biographical papers and documents can be found in file 11/10.
  - Obituary and bookmark from Memorial Gathering, 2010 July 4 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Honorable Discharge (Army Transportation Corp.), 1943 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - High school annual Pioneer edition the Olympus 1937 High school annual Olympiad 1939 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Awards and Certificates re: Writing and Journalism, 1954-1990 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Awards and Crtificates re: Photography, 1978 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Awards and Certificates, Other, 1946-1984 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Passports, vaccination records, 1971-1987 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1977 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Notebook "Eldon: The List Maker" and loose lists (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Postcards (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Pocket notebook(with wallet sized photographs inside), 1939-1942 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Seaman's Certificate of Identification, 1942 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - School Diplomas, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 1/13)
- Materials: Research and Writings, 1849-2012; 1937-2009; Series II.
  - Olympia, High School and College Writings
    - First manuscripts (high school), 1937-1938 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Large envelope – YMCA Olympia Washington Newsletter 1943, copies of the Olympus, Olympia high school newsletter 1938-1939, the Martian, St. Martin’s College v.18, nrs.4,6, November 14, 1941, Whatnot (Olympia High School March 24, 1939, 1938-1943 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - General research files
    - Anasazi - Southwest Tribes, circa 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Anthropology & Archaeology Prehistoric Phenomena (Archeoastrology, etc), 1970-1990 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Appaloosa, 1960s-2000s (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Archaeology Guatemala, Mexico, 1970s-2000s (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Archives (archiving), 1982-1993 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Artists (painters, sculptors, etc.), 1965-1995 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Autumn (N. Cascades), 1980-1997 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Chet Ullin – Mt. Baker Avalanche, 1939; 1965-2002 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Edwin Ayer’s Sojourn, 1849-1901 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Jane Barnes (Chippie and the Chinook), 1977-1989 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Saint Benedict, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Bighorn Pryor Mustangs, Medicine Wheel, Lovell, 1974-1994 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Bill Brown (“Blanket Bill”) Oregon, 1878-1995 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Birds, Beasts, & Butterflies, 1977-1998 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Black Panthers, 1983-2006 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - The Blues, Seasonal Affective Disorder (SAD), 1978-1996 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Logging boots (& other clothes), 1971-1993 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Bohunk Nelson & other logging stories, 1983 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - British Columbia, 1947-2000 (Box-folder 1b/34)
    - Bug Business, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Gladys Buroker (Bellingham Female Pilot ~1919), 1992-2002 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - George Washington Bush (African-American Washington/Oregon pioneer--Bush Prairie near Olympia, Washington), 1963-1977 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - The C.C.C. (Civilian Conservation Corps) regional, national, 1983-1994 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Dig it now - Grays Harbor-Puget Sound Canal Project, 1972-1984 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Christmas Conjunction (astronomy, Star of Bethlehem), 1975-1999 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Cannikan (Amchitka Nuclear Tests) First-hand observations, UPI notes, stories, 1942-2003 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Cannikan (Amchitka Nuclear Tests, Photographs), 1942-2003 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Copenhagen & Rothkilde (Roskilde), 1949-1987 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Chuckanut Drive, 1981-2000 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Columbus Day Storm, 1963-2002 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Columbia River, 1956-2001 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Columbia River(Newspaper clippings), 1956-2001 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - State Constitution (Washington) Writings, 1989 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Washington (State) Constitution (includes original from October 1878) (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Contact Lens (eyes), 1960-1986 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Cowboy Cooking, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Crater Lake, Bend, Shaniko, Oregon, 1983-1998 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Days (special) holidays, etc., 1978-2002 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Destinations (Misc.), 1989-2003 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Diamond Lil, 1961-1986 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Dogfish, 1976-1997 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Earthquakes, Plate Tectonics, 1909-2000 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Eastern Washington (general), 1966-2002 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Martha Ellis Story (crossed plains in 1852, narratives), 1892-1908 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - England, Wales, 1977-1998 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Flacks (Bob Ward), 1978-1990 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Foos (Miki & Paul), plane crash 1975, “medical” flight, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 2/28)
    - Pete French (Frenchglen, Oregon), 1963-1995 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - French Canada, 1972-1994 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Galloping Gertie, 1940 (Tacoma Narrows bridge collapse), 1970-1990 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Garden Therapy, 1983-1996 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - First Gas Station (1907, Seattle, John McLean), 1964-1989 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Geoducks, 1957-1990 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Gingerbread (cooking), 1988-1994 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Governor Hotel, Olympia, Washington, 1970 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Great Basin National Park, Nevada (Lehman Caves), 1987-1999 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Ruth Beebe Hill, Hanta Yo, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Alta McClellan--Hardware Sales, Bellingham, 1996; 2002 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Head-Smashed-In Buffalo Jump, Alberta, Canada, 1972-1997 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Herbs, garlic, peppers, strawberries, 1970-1993 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Herring, 1989 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - High Desert of Oregon (Harney – Lake – Malheur – Grant), 1962-2007 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Highway 20, 1984-2003 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Hippofinks (Fort Lawton, Washington, Anzac unit, defended Tobrak, military), 1942-1977 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Hoh-Quinault Rain Forest, 1966-1998 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Hose fight (Amtrak), 1995 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Old Bellingham Houses, Buildings, 1983-1997 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Hovander House (fragrance garden), 1984-1999 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Idaho, 1974-1994 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Miscellaneous Indian, treaties, info, etc., 1937-2005 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Indian Resorts & Casinos, 1979-1988 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Inventions, Inventors, etc., 1981-1999 (Box-folder 3/23)
    - John Day Fossils, 1955-2005 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Bobby Kennedy, et.al., 1974-1988 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - King Arthur, 1974-1998 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Kinseys (photographers), 1981-1992 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Kites, 1976-2006 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Klondike Kate (Mrs. John Matson, Bend, Oregon), 1939-1992 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Charles Lappenbusch, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Ham Lewis (Rep. James Hamilton Lewis, Washington State), 1897; 1995-2006 (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Logger Lingo, History of Logging, 1953-1997 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Lutefisk, 1974-2001 (Box-folder 3/33)
    - Mexico, Guatemala, 1973-2006 (Box-folder 3/34)
    - Mima Mounds (“Pimples Prairie”) S. of Olympia, Washington, 1956-2006 (Box-folder 3/35)
    - Montezuma Castle, Arizona, 1972-1995 (Box-folder 3/36)
    - Never Say Die (undertaker, Everett, Washington), 1891; 1973-1986 (Box-folder 3/37)
    - New England, Boston, 1968-1995 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - New Orleans, 1960-1992 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - North Cascade Park, Highway, 1950s-2008 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Oaxaca, 1973-2003 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Old Capitol (Olympia, Washington), 1949-1996 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Olympia (Washington), 1930s-1993 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Olympic Peninsula, Port Townsend, 1974-1996 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Oregon Coast, 1974-2000 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Oregon-Washington Roads, Parks, Sites, etc., 1961-1998 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - WWU’s Outdoor Art, 1980-2001 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Owl Party (~1986, Washington State politics), 1977-2004 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Palacio de Belles Artes, Mexico City, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Peace Arch, Sam Hill, 1969-2000 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Pickle Ball (invented by Washington Lt. Governor Joel Pritchard, et.al.), 1977-2006 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - General George Pickett (San Juan Pig War), 1926-1999 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Political Humor (Washington State), 1964-1999 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Port Townsend Southern Railway, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 4/17)
    - A Punny Thing Happened (travel humor, eg, Coals to Newcastle), 1974 (Box-folder 4/18)
    - Rare & Poisonous Plants, 1977-2004 (Box-folder 4/19)
    - St. Patrick’s (Irish toasts, etc), 1978-1995 (Box-folder 4/20)
    - Western Washington (Puget Sound), 1977-1993 (Box-folder 4/21)
    - Quagmire Jones, 1990 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Mt. Rainier, 1916-2001 (Box-folder 4/23)
    - Rembrandt (local couple’s discovery), 1972 (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Restaurants & Cooks, 1971-1992 (Box-folder 4/25)
    - Rocks, Fossils, Gems, 1975-2003 (Box-folder 4/26)
    - Gene Savoy (Bellingham) -- Andean Explorers Club, 1966-2004 (Box-folder 4/27)
    - Scablands, Grand Coulee, 1971-2008 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Scandinavia (Sweden), circa 1980s (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Scotland, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - The Seasons, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Seattle (general), 1968-2000 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Seowyn (Lummi Indian-initiation), 1980-1990 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Septober in Alaska, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Shannon Point (squid), 1974-1996 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Shollos (Mexican hairless dog), 1976-1998 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Shrove Tuesday, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Silk Train (Japanese trade), 1968-1996 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Skagit Flats, tulips, La Conner, Sedro-Woolley, Mt Vernon, Anacortes, 1961-2007 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Smorgasbord, 1976-1985 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Snake River, Hells Canyon, (Wallowa)(Hell’s Canyon)(1956 map), 1974-1999 (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Snakes and Reptiles, 1992 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Stone Soup, 1987 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Save the Tree Squeek, circa 1984 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - State Symbols, 1977-1997 (Box-folder 5/18)
    - Steelhead, 1967-1994 (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Steens Mountain, Alvord Desert, Jordan Valley, Malheur (Oregon), 1963-2003 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Sweden - Country of quality, 1983-1994 (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Tansy Ragwort, 1970-2000 (Box-folder 5/22)
    - Thermopolis Hot Springs, Colorado, 1962-1981 (Box-folder 5/23)
    - Tillinghast (seed company), 1983-1989 (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Tilt-top table, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Tomatoes & other vegetables, 1975-2005 (Box-folder 5/26)
    - Tools, 1977-1989 (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Trees (special), 1941-2000 (Box-folder 5/28)
    - Harry Truman, 1978-1995 (Box-folder 5/29)
    - Vanport Flood, 1978 (Box-folder 5/30)
    - Velikovsky (astronomy), 1972-1983 (Box-folder 5/31)
    - The Virginian & Guy Waring, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 5/32)
    - Volcanoes of the Cascades, 1974-2000 (Box-folder 5/33)
    - Volcanoes of the Cascades (Newspaper clippings), 1975-2005 (Box-folder 5/34)
    - Washington (George and Nat), 1974-1991 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Weather Lore, 1978-1993 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Wherries (boats) Ron Mueller, circa 2003 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - The Wild West, 1971-1991 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Wilkes, Charles (U.S. exploring expedition), 1959-1987 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Williwaw Christmas (Alaska, WWII), 1984-2005 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Wobblies (IWW, labor clash 1916), 1964-1998 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Yakima Indian Nation, treaties, legal, etc., 1955-1986 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Crime/Maritime/Sports
    - Misc.Crimes - Seattle, British Columbia, 1955-1990 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Kent Berry, circa 1939; 1984 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Jake Bird, circa 1948-1949 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - D.B. Cooper, 1972-2007 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Kryeacos murder, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Laura Law murder, circa 1940-1950 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Matnap, 1965-2006 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - DeCastro Earl Mayer, 1938-1979 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Michael Olds, circa 1961-1978 (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Peel murder case, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Raoul Guy Rockwell, circa 1960 (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Rum runners/Bootlegging, 1960-1994 (Box-folder 6/20)
    - Thelma Swensen, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Tornow/Wildman of the Oxbow, 1963-1993 (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Alaska steam, 1960-1982 (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Tommy Drake, 1931-1973 (Box-folder 6/24)
    - The Equator (Robert Louis Stevenson), 1962-1987 (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Merchant marine, 1967-1998 (Box-folder 6/26)
    - The Nautilus and the Missouri, 1979-2002 (Box-folder 6/27)
    - Old 75 (re: battle of the Aleutian Islands), Alaska, 1943-2000 (Box-folder 6/28)
      Writings/clippings/correspondence and photographs, re: battle of the Aleutian Islands Brown binder
    - Puget Sound shipping and vessels/ferries, 1954-1998 (Box-folder 6/29)
    - Shipwrecks and lighthouses/ the Coast Guard, 1939-1997 (Box-folder 6/30)
    - Tall ships of the sea, 1963-1998 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Tatoosh Triangle, 1958-1995 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - The Thayer (ship), 1974-1988 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - The Vigilant (ship), 1990-1992 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - The Wawona (ship), 1964-2009 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Baseball, 1971-1994 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Basketball, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Boxing, 1957-2005 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Fish, 1981-1996 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Football, 1981-2000 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Horse racing, 1989-2005 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Swimming, 1955-1979 (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Writing/Ideas/Poetry
    - Background for novel – “The Nakhodka Konspiracy”, 1979-1992 (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Unlabeled folder (Writing and copyright), 1957-2009 (Box-folder 7/14)
    - South-east Alaska ferry trip, 1976-2006 (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Cutlines and I.D.s (includes photo identification sheets for various articles), 2000-2008 (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Unlabeled (Various Barrett writings and clippings), 1981-1992 (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Photo markets and sales, 1975-2000 (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Seattle/Pacific Northwest manuscripts (includes photo identification sheets for various articles), 1980-2006 (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Food book, 1975-2006 (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Good writing/jokes/misc, 1946-1999 (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Miscellaneous writers, 1940-1999 (Box-folder 7/22)
    - UPI (contains September 1992 UPI Downhold Club Directory), 1989-1994 (Box-folder 7/23)
    - Travel brochures, 1960s-1990s (Box-folder 7/24)
  - Other research files
    Many of these files appear to be source material for Eldon Barrett’s later Bellingham Herald “Seniors” columns.
    - Monsters (Mostly about Sasquatch), circa 1930s-1940s; 1969-2001 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Gardening (includes “Sunset’s Garden Handbook” First edition, 1935), 1935-1999 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Gardening Master Gardener Textbook, 1984 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Abuse, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Book reviews, undated (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Kris Bulcroft- Old Love, 1979-1991 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Education Elder Hostel, 1984-1998 (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Exercise/fitness/diet, 1984-1991 (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Kingdome, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Long-term care/ dementia day-care, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Medical problems “medicare” (includes photograph of Lyndon Johnson signing Medicare and Medicaid into law – photo includes Mrs. Johnson, H. Humphrey, Harry S. and Bess Truman), 1983-1993 (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Memories/Oral history nostalgia, 1982-1993 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Peer-counseling, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Perks and services, 1984-1997 (Box-folder 8/14)
    - Pet therapy/music, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 8/15)
    - Photography notes (includes magazine: “The Photo-Miniature” August 1903, v.5, no.53), 1903-1984 (Box-folder 8/16)
    - Safety-accidents-emergency-hypothermia, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 8/17)
    - Social Security, 1982-2000 (Box-folder 8/18)
    - Taxes- finance, 1985-1995 (Box-folder 8/19)
    - Technology, 1985 (Box-folder 8/20)
    - Elderly travel, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 8/21)
    - U.S. Frigate Constitution (one brochure), 1933 (Box-folder 8/22)
    - Volunteering/RSVP caregivers/hospice, 1982-1992 (Box-folder 8/23)
    - Washington (State) Centennial, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 8/24)
    - Whatcom seniors - history and personalities, 1983-1991 (Box-folder 8/25)
    - Working, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 8/26)
    - Fraud, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 8/27)
    - Grandparenting, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 8/28)
    - Hobbies- gardening, etc., 1986-1992 (Box-folder 8/29)
    - Housing/home-sharing, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 8/30)
    - Legal matters- wills, etc., 1987-1994 (Box-folder 8/31)
    - Legislation- lobby, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 8/32)
    - Lifestyle/myths demographics, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 8/33)
  - Publications
    - Publications, 1965-1997 (Box-folder 8/34)
    - Michael Olds, murderer, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 8/35)
    - A Bag of Marbles (fiction), 1982-1983 (Box-folder 8/36)
    - Pacific Northwest - Flying Colors, 1980 (Box-folder 8/37)
    - Puget Sound Country – Flighttime, 1976 (Box-folder 8/38)
    - Seafair: Seattle’s nautical festival – Flying colors, July 1981 (Box-folder 8/39)
    - Seattle: rich in liquid assets – American Way, 1980 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Seattle: city for all seasons – Sky, 1982 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Space Needle – Accent, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Time to laugh – P.I./Northwest, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Washington/Oregon: the fourth corner – Flying Colors, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 9/5)